What?
Has the murderer, Kaburagi T. Kotetsu, lost his mind?!
なんと殺人犯 鏑木・Ｔ・虎徹
何を血迷ったのか
He's shown up in Wild Tiger's previous suit!
元祖ワイルドタイガーのスーツに
身を包み 姿を現しました
What is he planning to do?
何が狙いだ
Oh great... he's on our building.
おーい おーい
人んちのビルで
That man is such a nuisance!
迷惑な男だ
He sure is.
ホントホント
It's dangerous here!
ここも危ないですよ
Please evacuate!
避難してください
Don't shove! Move out in a single file.
押さないで 押さないで
順番に外へ
うんっ
Heroes! I won't run or hide anymore!
ヒーロー諸君
俺はもう 逃げも隠れもしねえぞ
はあー
はっ
あっ
Let's do this.
行くぞ
yabureta PAGE wa ubawaretanda yo
That torn page was stolen,
破れたページは
奪われたんだよ
dokoka de otoshita oboe wa nai kara
since I don't remember ever dropping it anywhere.
何処かで落とした
覚えはないから
iwakan mo nai hodo kirei ni nai soko ni wa
In the place where the page used to be,
違和感もないほど
綺麗にないそこには
yume to iu nano shou ga tashikani atta
there was a chapter entitled "Dreams."
夢という名の章が確かにあった
nani wo nikumeba ii? kako ka jibun jishin ka
But who should I blame? The past? Myself?
何を憎めばいい？
過去か自分自身か
dekireba hoka no dareka de are
If possible, I hope it's someone else.
出来れば他の誰かであれ
monogatari no bokura ga sono mirai wo omou no wa
We, the characters in the story, think of the future.
物語の僕らが
その未来想うのは
nakushita ato demo shuyaku wa kawarenai kara
Because even after we're gone, the main character can't change.
失くした後でも
主役は変われないから
shousan nante sarenakutatte tashikana kyou ga aru nara
Even if I'm not praised, as long as today is here,
賞賛なんてされなくたって
確かな今日があるなら
yume nante namae no shou wa ikura demo tsukurerunda
I can make as many chapters as I want entitled "Dreams."
夢なんて名前の章は
いくらでも創れるんだ
では 向かいます
I'm going in, sir.
Wait.
待て
Let's see what Kaburagi Kotetsu is going to do.
ここは鏑木虎徹の出方をうかがうぞ
It doesn't matter what he does! I will capture him at any cost!
奴が何をしてこようが問題ありません
僕が必ず捕まえて見せます
そうやって 感情的になるのは
君の唯一の欠点だ
Your wild emotions are your only flaw.
You need to simmer down.
冷静になりなさい
んっ
うっ
The murderer, Kaburagi, has activated his powers.
殺人犯 鏑木 能力を発動し
一体何をしようというのか
What is he planning to do?!
I have a plan.
秘策があるんですよ
さあ　お前の秘策とやらを見せてみろ
All right, let's see what this plan of yours is.
Watch closely.
よーく見とけよ
はっ あーー
あーー
ほっ
ええ？
Look at this pose!
ほーら このポーズ
このスーツ 見覚えあんだろ
And this suit! Don't they all look familiar?!
I'm the original Wild Tiger who worked with you guys on HERO TV!
お前らと一緒にヒーローＴＶを
支えてきた 元祖ワイルドタイガーだよ
That's your plan?
秘策ってそれか
You can't deny that you all recognize me!
この姿を見て
思い出さないはずねえよな
Look! Wild roar!
ほらっ ワイルドに吠えるぜ
ほらっ
See that?
Dressing up like Tiger after what you've done?
この期に及んでタイガーの
コスプレだなんて　おふざけが過ぎるわ
You've gone too far.
Huh?
はっ
Don't think you can fool us with that cheap imitation suit!
安っぽいおもちゃスーツで
ほざいてんじゃねえ
えっ おもちゃじゃねえよ
本物だ
It's not an imitation! It's the real thing!
おお
あっ
何してんの
What are you doing?! Capture the suspect!
犯人確保
Yes, ma'am!
了解
Play time is over for you...
余興はここまでだ
My maximum wind velocity for today is off the charts!
今日の私は最大風速
計測！　不能！
はあーっ
だあっ
へぇっ えっ
Hey, hold on.
おっちょい 待て待てっ
おいっ
おっ待てっ　つってんだろ
Wait, I say!
ふあっ
どひゃっ えいっ
Aww, jeez!
あーもう
ちょこまか目障りね
Stay still, you're annoying!
Wait! Listen to me.
えー 待ってくれ　話を…
We're not listening to your excuses, you lowlife!
言い訳なんか聞くか
うせろー
だあっ
うっ
We Heroes have you surrounded. You cannot escape.
我々ヒーローに囲まれて
逃げられると思うな
落ち着けって
Calm down! I'll prove to you I'm the real deal right now!
俺が本物だってこと
今 証明してやっから
Hey, Dragon Kid.
なあ ドラゴンキッド
Huh?
あっ
俺達で市長の子供を
預かったことあったよな
Remember the time we babysat the mayor's son?
あっ
I know that ever since then, you've been wearing
あれ以来
親からもらったシオンの髪飾りを
お前がつけるようになったこと
the shion flower hairpin that your parents gave you.
俺知ってるぞ
I only wear it when I'm out of uniform.
素顔の時しかつけないのに
何で知ってるの？
How do you know about that?!
Blue Rose.
ブルーローズ
あっ
I know that you actually wanted to
お前はホントはヒーローじゃなく
歌手を目指してたんだって
become a singer instead of a Hero.
俺知ってる
どうしてそれを
How do you know about that?
Origami!
折紙
ああっ
When we went to the Hero Academy for a special campaign,
キャンペーンで
ヒーローアカデミーに行った時
“自分がヒーローに向いてない”って
悩んでたよな
you told me that you feared
you weren't cut out to be a Hero, didn't you?
What?!
ええっ
Sky High!
スカイハイ
お前 目玉焼きの黄身をこうやって
You like to suck the yolks out of fried eggs like this,
...don't you?
すするの好きだよな
はあああ
Fire Emblem, you shave your facial hair and armpits
ファイヤーエンブレムは朝昼晩
ひげと脇の手入れをしてるよな
three times a day, don't you?
いやっ
Oh, my!
What's going on here?
おっと これはどういうことだ
犯人が次々と
ヒーローの暴露話を始めました
The suspect is exposing each of the Heroes' personal secrets!
What's with this guy? How does he know all of this?
何なんだあいつ
次から次へ
ああっ
Could it be?
まさかこの人
Yes! You remember?!
おおっ 思い出したのか
You're a stalker!
ストーカー
そーじゃねえよ
No, I'm not!
These are real memories of the times we spent together!
正真正銘 俺達の思い出じゃねえか
You guys still won't believe me after everything I just said?
これだけ言ってもわかんねえのかよ
Come on, guys!
なっお前ら ホントにこの俺が
人を殺すような奴に見えんのか
Do I really look like someone who would kill a person?
うん
Yes.
ああ
Really?
そんな
This is the end of the road for you.
貴様の運命もここまでだな
うっ
ねっ
No, you don't.
見えない
Huh?
えっ？
おっ？
I can't see this person as being a murderer.
私にはどうしても
この人が人殺しには見えないよ
ブルーローズ
Blue Rose...
もし本当に殺人犯なら
If he really is the murderer,
こんなことしてまで
自分の無実を訴えようとする？
then why is he trying so hard to prove his innocence?
騙されんな
Don't be fooled!
えっ
He's trying to trick us by gaining our sympathy,
情に訴えて たぶらかそうったって
そうはいかねえぞ
but that's not going to work!
よせよ バイソン
Stop, Bison!
You still haven't returned the 20 dollars you owe me!
お前 俺が貸した20ドル
まだ返してねんだぞ
何をゲス野郎
Shut up, you lowlife!
どあっと
あっ
Believe me! I'm innocent!
信じてくれ 俺は無実だ
Is this the best he can do?
所詮 こんなものか
Have you calmed down, Barnaby?
そろそろ落ち着いたかい
バーナビー
Yes.
ええ
The murderer is unable to do anything against our six Heroes.
我らがヒーロー６人を前に
殺人犯　手も足も出ない
サンキュー 鏑木虎徹
Thank you, Kaburagi Kotetsu.
あっ
Hello?
はい
I'm sorry.
すまなかったね
I just sent out my company's Hero,
今 わが社のヒーローを出動させたが
間に合いそうにない
but it looks like he won't make it in time.
It's okay, sir.
いえ 他のヒーローの活躍で
番組は今季最高視聴率をマークしました
Thanks to the other Heroes,
our show has just marked the highest rating of this season.
それなら良かった
That's good to hear.
では さらなる数字を目指して
今後の展開でも話し合おうか
Let's talk about what we'll do to get even higher numbers.
Hey... You guys really plan to arrest me?
なあ 本気で俺を捕まえる気かよ
You don't know when to give up, do you?
往生際の悪い男だな
You can make your confession in prison.
懺悔はムショでおし
あっああ
What happened?
何があったんだよ
Why?
何で…
何で思い出してくれねえんだよ
Why won't you guys remember?!
でっ
All right!
おーっと 殺人犯 鏑木・Ｔ・虎徹
The murderer, Kaburagi T. Kotetsu, has been arrested!
これで逮捕だ
Wait!
待って
えっ
My dad didn't do it!
お父さんは悪くない
Kaede? Why are you here?
楓 何でここに
Dad?
お父さん？
What's this?
どうした 突然現れた少女が
無実を訴えているようですが
A young girl has suddenly appeared
and is pleading that the suspect is innocent.
うーん
Young lady, this person has done something very bad.
お嬢ちゃん
この人はとても悪いことをしたんだ
That's a lie!
嘘だよ そんなの
I understand how you feel, but we need to take him away.
気持ちはわかるけど
連れてかなきゃいけないの
いやだっ いやだ いやだ いやだ
No! No, no, no!
困ったわね
Oh dear...
おっ
My dad...
お父さんを…
お父さんを返して
Give me back my dad!
はっ
あっ
ぬおっ
おっ
あっ 楓
Kaede?
What?
これは
What the heck?
なんだ
Mr. Maverick?
社長？
Ms. Agnes, we've got a problem!
アニエスさん 大変です
中継が遮断されました
Our signal has been jammed!
What?! What's causing it?
何ですって　原因は？
I don't know!
わかりません
ええっ
あっ
うーん
Huh?
あれ？
おっ 僕たち何やってたんだっけ
What were we doing?
何ってタイガーを逮捕しようとしてたに
決まってる
We were about to arrest Tiger, of course.
どうして タイガーを
But why would we do that?
Because he killed someone, and...
それは確か 殺人を
Huh?
えっ？
I'm not sure why,
なんだ この記憶
but we were definitely treating Mr. Tiger like a criminal.
でも確かに拙者たち
タイガーさんを犯人扱いして
But that's impossible, right?
そんなこと ありえないのに
ねえ
Anyway, why are you dressed like that?
っつうか お前
何でそんなかっこしてんだ
Yeah, you look weird.
ほーんとだ 変なの
You guys remember me?
思い出してくれたのか
Huh?
は？
You guys finally remember who I am!
俺のことやっと思い出してくれたのか
Hey, Dad!
ねえ ちょっとお父さん
Oh yeah, Kaede!
ああ そうだ 楓
Why are you here?
お前なんでここに
Why didn't you tell me?!
どうして黙ってたの？
Huh?
えっ
Why didn't you tell me that you were a Hero, Dad?!
お父さんがヒーローだってこと
Oh, well, you see...
ああ… いや いやっそれ
うーん
ああ
Well, I wasn't trying to hide it.
別に隠すつもりは なかったんだ
ただ余計な心配かけたくなくて
It's just that I didn't want you to worry about me.
うーん
ああ
I'm sorry for lying to you all this time.
ごめんな 今まで嘘ついて
Don't treat me like a little kid.
子供扱いしないでよね
Oh! That aside, what did you do, Kaede?!
ああっ それより楓
さっき何したんだ
What was that white ball of light you created?
白い玉見たいの出したろ
わかんないよ
I don't know. It just happened.
気づいたらそうなってて
Does that mean she copied that power from someone?
じゃあ ああいう能力を
誰かからコピーしたってことか
うっ え？
Huh?
Did you touch anyone recently?
最近誰かに触ったりしてねえか
Let's see...
えーと
You're one of Barnaby's fans, aren't you? Thank you.
お嬢ちゃんはバーナビーの
ファンなんだね　ありがとう
Oh!
ああっ ビルの１階であった人だ
I ran into a person when I was on the first floor of this building!
What did he look like?
それ どんな奴だった
うんとー 眼鏡のおじさん
He was an old man with glasses!
ちょうちょのネクタイしてたよ
He had a neck tie!
あっ
Maverick...
マーベリック
ん？
Hey, don't leave us in the dark.
ちょいと あたしたちおいて
話進めないでよ
We don't know what's going on here.
何が何だかさっぱり
Maverick is behind everything.
すべての黒幕はマーベリックだ
Huh?
えっ
Maverick used his powers to manipulate your memories.
お前たちはマーベリックの能力で
記憶を操作されてたんだよ
うっ
Our memories?
記憶を
Yeah.
ああ それでうちのが
ＮＥＸＴの力でお前たちをもとに
And my kid restored you guys
back to normal with her NEXT powers.
イヒヒヒ
When did he manipulate our memories?
いつ記憶の操作なんか
As I recall, we were all summoned by Mr. Maverick, and...
確か 我々はマーベリック氏に
呼び出されて
Who else was there?
その席に他に誰かいたか？
アニエスさんと あと
タイガーの会社の人たちも
Ms. Agnes... and people from your company.
He was trying to frame me by changing the memories
俺の素顔を知る奴の記憶を操って
俺をはめようとしたって訳か
of everyone who knew my identity, huh?
すまんでござる
I'm very sorry! Because of us...
拙者たちのせいで
If only I had realized it
目玉焼きのくだりの時に
気づいていればこんなことには
when you started talking about fried eggs...
Don't worry about it.
気にすんな
思い出してくれたならそれで
I'm just glad that you all remember now.
Tiger... I...
タイガー 私
Thanks.
うれしかったよ
Huh?
はっ
You were the only one who tried to believe me.
お前だけは俺のことを
信じようとしてくれたろ
ありがとな
Thanks.
はっ うっ
You, on the other hand...
それに引き替え
お前完全に犯人扱いだったな
You treated me like a total criminal!
Strange... My memory seems to be all fuzzy...
んっ あれえ 記憶がいまいち…
“ゲス野郎”とおっしゃってましたよね
You called me a lowlife, didn't you?
And twice at that!
それも２回
Forget about that, Tiger.
あっ そんなことよりタイガー
あの子が噂の楓ちゃんだろ
So is that little Kaede you've always been talking about?
早く紹介してくれよ
Why don't you introduce her to us?
あっそうだった
Oh, that's right!
Sorry for the late introduction, but this is my daughter Kaede!
紹介遅れたけど 娘の楓だ
Pleased to meet you. I'm Kaburagi Kaede.
はじめまして 鏑木楓です
Hi there.
どうも
Nice to meet you.
はじめまして
Thank you for saving us.
かたじけない
助けてくれて
いえ お父さんが
いつもお世話になってます
It's okay. Thank you for always helping out my dad!
How admirable. That's a good greeting.
偉いぞ グッドなあいさつだ
Where's Barnaby?
ねえ バーナビーは
えっ
Huh?
バーナビーに会いたい
I want to meet Barnaby!
That's right. There's still Barnaby...
あっそうだ まだあいつが
Were Barnaby's memories changed too?
まさか バーナビーも記憶を
Most likely.
多分な
うわっ
貴様だけは許せない
I will never forgive you.
You'll pay for killing Aunt Samantha!
よくもサマンサおばさんを
なっ
Barnaby?
バーナビー
バーナビー？
It's all a misunderstanding, Handsome!
誤解よ ハンサム
Mr. Tiger isn't the murderer!
タイガーさんは犯人じゃないよ
Stop, it's no use!
よせ 無駄だ
But...
でも
Kaede, do what you did earlier!
楓 さっきやったのと
同じことをするんだ
は？
Huh?
Right now, Barnaby is being brainwashed by a bad person...
バーナビーは今 悪い奴に洗脳されてる
We need your power to save him!
あいつを救うには
楓の能力が必要なんだ
Got it.
わかった
Hey, Barnaby.
おい バーナビー
今 全部思い出させてやるからな
We're going to make you remember everything!
はあーっ
あっ
Huh?
あらっ
あれれ
What the—?
えっええ 何だ
Oh, come to think of it, just now...
あっ そういえばさっき
How admirable. That's a good greeting.
偉いぞ グッドなあいさつだ
You idiot!
おいっ
Huh?
えっ
Because of you, Kaede's abilities have changed!
お前のせいで楓の能力が
変わっちまったじゃねえか
What did I do?
私が何か？
この子はな 触った相手の能力を
コピーするＮＥＸＴなんだよ
She's a NEXT who copies the powers of the people she touches!
What?!
ええっ
I'm sorry! I didn't know.
すまない そうだと知らなくて
Damn! She was our only chance!
くそっ 唯一の切り札が
Those fools.
愚かな奴らだ
Out of the way. My business is with that man.
どいてください
用があるのはその男です
Barnaby! We've been tricked! Maverick is behind everything!
バーナビー 俺達ははめられたんだよ
黒幕はマーベリックだ
ふざけるな
I've heard enough!
でやっ
はーっ
Calm down, Barnaby!
落ち着け バーナビー
えいっ
He's your partner!
彼はあなたのパートナーよ
そうだよ 思い出して
That's right. Try to remember!
What are you talking about? That man is a murderer!
何をバカなことを
その男は殺人犯ですよ
Barnaby!
バーナビー
邪魔しないでください
Don't interfere!
Barnaby. Snap out of it!
バーナビー君
目を覚ますんだ
Let go!
離せ
Kaburagi Kotetsu! Why did you kill Aunt Samantha?!
鏑木虎徹
なぜ サマンサおばさんを殺した
答えろ
Answer me!
Take care of Kaede if anything happens to me.
俺に何かあったら楓を頼む
What?
えっ
All right... If that's the case,
よーし こうなったら
イヤっちゅうほど俺を思い出させてやる
I'll make you remember whether you want to or not!
Come get me, Barnaby!
ついて来い バーナビー
えいっ
おおっ
だあっ
お父さん
Dad!
Don't!
待って
It's too dangerous.
危ないよ
でも
But...
It's all right.
大丈夫
Your dad is a Hero.
君のお父さんはヒーローだ
ん
ああ
ドヤッ
うーん
えっ
うん
Oh! I'm not anyone suspicious!
ああ 自分は決して
怪しい者ではありません
あっまあ 怪しいですけど
Well, I do look suspicious, but...
何を言っているんだい タイガー
Huh?
えっ
なんだい さっきの茶番は
私のスーツを差し置いて
あんな恰好でテレビに出て
Your memories...
ああ 記憶
Wait, were you watching the broadcast?
もしかして中継見て
へ？
You remember me now!
思い出してくれたんですね
おおっ
おっおおっおっおっ
あっ
Hey, Barnaby. What took you so long?
よお バーナビー遅かったな
How did you get that suit and that motorcycle?!
貴様がなぜそのスーツとバイクを
A black suit and a red motorcycle, eh?
黒いスーツと赤いバイクか
前のスーツの方が似合ってんぞ
I think you looked way better in your old suit.
Come on!
さあ 来い
なっ
Remember this?
覚えてるか
お前がそっち 俺がこっちで
何度も犯人追いかけたろ
We would go chasing down criminals with you
sitting on that side and me on this side!
Shut up!
黙れ
Calm down, Barnaby!
落ち着け バーナビー
That's dangerous!
あぶねえって
Look in front of you!
おい 前 前
おっ
What's that?
なんだ
わあーーー
Tiger...
タイガー
And Barnaby!
アンド バーナビー
Hey, up ahead!
おい 前
おっ
どわっ
Doesn't this place bring back memories?
どうだ 懐かしいだろ
お前と俺が初めて出会った場所だ
It's the place where we first met.
You carried me in your arms after saving me, remember?
あん時 お前
俺のことお姫様抱っこしたろ
I would never do that!
する訳ないだろ
うっ
あっ
It's okay. Those two will be fine.
心配しないで
あの２人ならきっと
Hey, stop!
おい やめろ
Stop, I said!
やめろって
どわっ
Cut it out!
いい加減にしろ
Oops...
おわっ
You bastard...
貴様 反撃か
You attacked me!
いやっ 違うって
It's not what you think!
Tiger?
タイガー
No. It's the person we were persuaded to believe was him.
否 そう思いこまされていた
別人でござる
Who are you?!
てめえ 何者だ
あたしら騙すなんて
火傷じゃすまないわよ
You're not getting off with light burns for fooling us.
Now show me your power.
さあ見せてくれ 君のその力を
Reveal yourself, Wild Imposter!
正体を現せ
偽ワイルド
はっ
Guess I have no choice...
しょうがねえ
やるしかねえか
Let's do this!
Good Luck Mode.
へあーーー
ふあーーー
灰色に染まる街の片隅で
hai iro ni somaru machi no katasumi de souzou dake no yume wo miteita
In an obscure corner of the ashen city, I was having a surreal dream.
想像だけの夢をみていた
存在する事の意味を
sonzai suru koto no imi wo nantonaku kangaehajimeta
I started to think about the meaning of existence.
なんとなく考え始めた
But I never know
BUT, I NEVER KNOW.
But, I never know.
myself＆夢＆
MYSELF AND yume AND TRUE AND ANYMORE
Myself & dreams & truth & anymore.
true＆Anymore
もう… もっと…
mou... motto...
At all...
こんな世界で私に聞いたの
konna sekai de watashi ni kita no ittai nani ga dekiru no ka wo
I asked myself what one can do in a world like this.
一体何が出来るのかを
あなたの笑顔が教えてくれたような
anata no egao ga oshiete kureta youna sonna kigashita kara
And I felt that your smiling face could teach me the answer.
そんな気がしたから
光を見つけたような
hikari wo mitsuketa youna itami ni furerareru
And enabled me to be touched by the pain of finding light.
痛みに触れられる
そう そんな気がした
sou, sonna kigashita
Yes, that was the feeling.
人は皆儚い夢を
hito wa mina hakanai yume wo kono te ni ireru tame ni
In pursuing their fleeting dreams,
この手に入れる為に
永遠の真実さえ見失う
eien no shinjitsu sae miushinau
people lose sight of the eternal truth.
消えない悲しい明日に
kienai kanashii asu ni hikari wo kureta no wa daredemo naku tatta hitori
No one made me realize that there is a light that never dims but you,
光をくれたのは
誰でもなく たった一人
過去も未来も
shinjitai
I want to believe.
kako mo mirai mo wakachiaeru zutto
always sharing the past and the future.
分かち合えるずっと
ども TIGER ＆ BUNNYの
足の裏にホクロがあるほう
虎徹です
Hi! I'm Kotetsu, the member of Tiger & Bunny
なっ バーナビー 頼むから早く
思い出してくれ
who has a mole on the bottom of his foot!
Come on, Barnaby, hurry up and remember me!
じゃなきゃ 俺 もう
次回　TIGER ＆ BUNNY
If you don't, I...
ミスフォーチュン…
不幸は単独では来ない
Next time on Tiger & Bunny:
Misfortunes never come singly.